Guide to the Gina Johnson Riot Grrrl Zines MSS.524
Fales Library and Special Collections
Gina Johnson Riot Grrrl Zines
1993-1995
Fales Library and Special Collections
Johnson-Cuomo, Gina
MSS.524
0.25 Linear Feet in one half manuscript box
The Gina Johnson Riot Grrrl Zines collection contains materials gathered by Johnson for her research as a graduate student in the early to mid-1990s. Johnson collected a number of zines revolving around the Riot Grrrl movement during this time to support her research interests. This collection consists of issues of Riot Grrrl zines, such as My Last Nerve, Wild Honey Pie, and The Nerdy Grrrl Revolution. The selected zines combine illustrations, personal narratives, poetry, reviews, and social criticism centering around issues of gender, race, sexuality, and equality. The collection ranges from 1993 to 1995.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials collected by Gina Johnson-Cuomo from the early to mid-1990s documenting her research interest in the Riot Grrrl movement. Materials include issues of Riot Grrrl zines, such as My Last Nerve, Wild Honey Pie, and The Nerdy Grrrl Revolution. The zines combine illustrations, personal narratives, poetry, reviews, and social criticism centering around issues of gender, race, sexuality, and equality. The collection ranges from 1993 to 1995.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Gina Johnson-Cuomo in November 2017.
Biographical Note
Gina Johnson-Cuomo (née Gina Johnson) became interested in the Riot Girl movement in the 1990s. While in graduate school, she made the Riot Grrrl movement the subject of her graduate research. During this period, she collected zines published by women participating in the movement and used the materials for her research.
Riot grrrl movement.; Zines.; Women's rights.; Feminism; Punk culture.; Feminist music
- I'm So Fucking Beautiful #1 and #2 / I Love Me #1, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- When She was Good, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Gerrl Zine Distro, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Wild Honey Pie #9, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The Nerdy Grrrl Revolution #2, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lauren Hancock Zine, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Jigsaw #5, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Not Your Bitch #2, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Wild Honey Pie #8, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Fern #5, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Pussy Cat Vision #2, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Power Candy, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Out of the Vortex, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bulldozer #1, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Body Mine, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- My Last Nerve #1, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- New Zines!!!, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- My Last Nerve #2, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Rage #6, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- We Aren't the World #4, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)